# JUSTIN KIMBLE

## WEB DEVELOPER

# PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a web developer with professional experience in Content Management System development in a client-driven environment. As a huge coding geek, I love constantly learning new technologies and methods; development is my favorite hobby!

# SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- Frontend:
  - o HTML5, CSS, LESS, .NET, Bootstrap
- Backend / Server:
  - C#, PHP, SQL, MSSQL, JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, JSON, SFTP/FTP
- · Version Control (Git)
- Database Management (SQL, MySQL, MS SQL)
- Translating Adobe XD wireframes
- Object Oriented programming in backend solutions
- · Creative problem solving

## **SPECIALIZATIONS**

- Frontend Web Development
- CMS Development (WordPress, Hubspot)
- · Custom CMS Editors / Block Editors
- Modern, Responsive Development
- · ADA, WCAG Compliant Websites
- Gated Content Websites
- Full Stack WordPress Development

## CONTACT ME

- Mobile: (216) 387-8136
- Email: jkimble.dev@gmail.com

## EXPERIENCE

## **IUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER**

## Kaulig Media, Oct 2020 - Apr 2021

- Created responsive templates for web pages with multiple CMS
- · Developed custom blocks / editors to assist content loading
- Produced multi-platform HTML email campaigns for clients
- Participated in QA reviews with design and content teams
- Repaired and organized client website database

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

## The Karcher Group, Apr 2021 - June 2023

- Fully developed multiple comprehensive e-Commerce websites
- Developed modern, responsive Hubspot websites
- Made contributions to dozens of live websites
- · Worked with clients to create custom CMS solutions
- · Awarded Co-Employee of the Month
- Created custom JavaScript animations
- · Custom block editors and custom blocks
- Multiple full, custom websites developed with custom themes.

## **FREELANCE**

## Ongoing

- Designed and developed marketing website for dentistry practice, greatly increasing visibility online and increasing conversions.
- Designed and developed an eccentric, stylish photography site.

# **EDUCATION**

## MOUNT ST. MARY'S UNIVERSITY

# Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Aug 2016 - May 2020

- Track & Field Team Captain, 7x All-Conference, 2 School Records
- Board Member, Association of Computing Machinery (MSMU)
- Board Member, Black Student Union
- · Group App Development

## REFERENCES

- Chris Haag, Development Team Manager, The Karcher Group
  - Email: chaag@tkg.com
  - o Ask for phone number
- Dr. Julian Woods, DDS, Landover Dental Associates
  - o Email: jawoodsdds@gmail.com
  - o Phone: (443) 977-7974
  - Website. https://www.landover-dental.com (built by me!)